<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<itemrelease version="2.0">
  <passage id="3746" version="6" bankkey="187">
    <attriblist>
      <attrib attid="stm_pass_id">
        <name>Stim: ITS ID</name>
        <val>3746</val>
        <desc></desc>
      </attrib>
      <attrib attid="stm_pass_subject">
        <name>Stim: Subject</name>
        <val>ELA</val>
        <desc></desc>
      </attrib>
      <attrib attid="stm_pass_desc">
        <name>Stim: Description</name>
        <val>When Winning Took a Backseat 4770 - SBAC_Field</val>
        <desc></desc>
      </attrib>
    </attriblist>
    <resourceslist />
    <content language="ENU" version="2.0" approvedVersion="6">
      <title><![CDATA[&#xA0;]]></title>
      <author><![CDATA[&#xA0;]]></author>
      <stem><![CDATA[<p style="">Read the text. Then answer the questions.</p><p style=""><br /><span style="font-weight:bold; ">When Winning Took a </span><span id="passage_3746_TAG_1_BEGIN"><span style="font-weight:bold; ">Backseat</span></span><br /><span id="passage_3746_TAG_3_BEGIN">by</span> Bruce Nash and Allan <span id="passage_3746_TAG_2_BEGIN">Zullo</span><br /><br />Scott Bennett and Brad Howes grew up south of Salt Lake City in the fertile valley between the Jordan River and the towering Wasatch Mountains of Utah. The boys lived just far enough apart not to attend the same schools, but close enough to compete in the same leagues in baseball, football, and basketball.</p><p style=""><br />No matter whose team won, Scott and Brad always shook hands and complimented each other on the way they played. The two didn’t become close friends because they were always on opposite sides. But the boys grew up admiring each other’s athletic skills.</p><p style=""><br />And it was their childhood competition that forged a lasting friendship and set the stage for an extraordinary display of sportsmanship seldom seen in track and field.</p><p style=""><br />It happened while the boys were members of school cross-country teams—Scott at Murray High and Brad at nearby Cottonwood High. During meets, as they pounded out mile after mile across the empty fields, Scott and Brad formed an unspoken bond. They learned to respect one another’s competitive spirit and strengths. Brad liked to set a blistering pace early in the race, which wore down most other runners who tried to keep up with him. Scott, meanwhile, had a strong finishing kick, which had him breathing down the leader’s neck on the final stretch.</p><p style=""><br />Usually, the boys finished first and second when their schools competed. Sometimes Brad won; other times it was Scott who broke the tape first.</p><p style=""><br />Their most memorable race—the one track and field coaches still talk about—occurred during the 1970 cross-country regional meet, with the winner going to the state finals. The event, held as part of Cottonwood High’s homecoming festivities, was run during halftime of the football game between Cottonwood and Murray. Since the schools were only about ten miles apart, the stands were jammed with rooters from both sides.</p><p style=""><br />At halftime, Murray was leading by two touchdowns and threatening to spoil Cottonwood’s homecoming. So when Scott and Brad took their places at the starting line, each knew there was a lot more at stake than just a race. Brad felt that by winning he could salvage some of Cottonwood’s pride at homecoming. Scott wanted to win to prove that Murray was the best at everything.</p><p style=""><br />There were three other runners in the race, but all eyes were on Scott and Brad when the starter’s gun went off. The group circled the track that ringed the football field and headed out the exit for the 2.6-mile cross-country run.</p><p style=""><br />As expected, Brad quickly took the lead in a race that went through the rolling, grassy hills of Sugarhouse Park bordering the school grounds. At the halfway point, Brad had pulled ahead of Scott by nearly 300 yards while the other runners had fallen out of contention.</p><p style=""><br />Despite the gap, Scott wasn’t worried. In past races, Brad usually grabbed the lead, but Scott, with his strong finish, often caught Brad on the final stretch. Sticking to his race strategy, Scott steadily gained on Brad. By the time the two reached the stadium, Scott was only a couple of steps behind.</p><p style=""><br />When the pair dashed through the stadium tunnel and onto the track for the final lap, the capacity crowd rose to its feet to cheer the runners who were now racing stride for stride.</p><p style=""><br />But coming around the final turn, Scott cut to the inside to pass Brad and get in position for a sprint down the stretch. Just then, Brad also moved inside and the runners’ legs tangled. Both stumbled. Scott managed to keep his feet, but Brad sprawled headfirst onto the track.</p><p style=""><br />Scott ran a few more paces. But suddenly, he became aware of an eerie silence. The crowd that had been shouting moments before fell deathly silent when Brad tripped and hit the ground. So Scott stopped and looked back at his lifelong rival. Brad, whose knees and hands were scraped and bleeding from falling on the cinders, was struggling to regain his feet.</p><p style=""><br />Who won or lost the race no longer mattered to Scott. His friend and competitor was hurt. Scott knew what he had to do—he went back to help. “Give me your hand, Brad,” said Scott. “Let me help you.”</p><p style=""><br />Brad looked up at Scott, smiled, and said, “Man, you’re something else.” Scott pulled his injured rival to his feet but Brad was hurting so badly that he couldn’t run very well. So Scott put his arm around Brad and the two began trotting down the final stretch. The thousands of fans in the stands gasped when they saw Scott’s gallant gesture and then erupted into thunderous applause.</p><p style=""><br />Shocked by the unexpected spill, the track judges had dropped the tape that marked the finish line. “Get that tape back up!” a coach yelled. “They’re coming in . . . together!”</p><p style=""><br />With Brad limping the final 50 yards, and Scott helping him every step of the way, the two competitors crossed the finish line arm in arm. The coaches and the track judges then huddled over what to do about the incredibly unselfish act of sportsmanship they had just witnessed.</p><p style=""><br />“One of the runners has to win, but that doesn’t mean the other one has to lose,” said Scott’s coach, Sam Moore. “I know Scott wouldn’t want to have his victory tainted. I say we give both kids first place.”</p><p style=""><br />Moore’s suggestion won unanimous approval from Brad’s coach and the judges. The race was declared a dead heat.</p><p style=""><br />“I have never seen such sportsmanship,” said Moore. “I doubt if I ever will again.”</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">“When Winning Took a Backseat” by Bruce Nash and Allan Zullo, from <span style="font-style:italic; ">The Greatest Sports Stories Never Told</span><span style="font-style:normal; ">.</span> Copyright © 1993 by Nash &amp; Zullo Productions, Inc. Published by Simon &amp; Schuster for Young Readers. Used by permission of Nash &amp; Zullo Productions, Inc.</p>]]></stem>
      <attachmentlist>
        <attachment id="braillefile1" type="BRF" subtype="contracted" file="passage_3746_enu_contracted.brf" />
        <attachment id="braillefile2" type="BRF" subtype="uncontracted" file="passage_3746_enu_uncontracted.brf" />
      </attachmentlist>
      <apipAccessibility>
        <accessibilityInfo>
          <accessElement identifier="ae1">
            <contentLinkInfo itsLinkIdentifierRef="passage_3746_TAG_1_BEGIN" type="Text">
              <objectLink />
            </contentLinkInfo>
            <relatedElementInfo>
              <readAloud>
                <textToSpeechPronunciation>Backseat.</textToSpeechPronunciation>
                <textToSpeechPronunciationAlternate>Backseat</textToSpeechPronunciationAlternate>
              </readAloud>
              <brailleText>
                <brailleTextString>Backseat</brailleTextString>
              </brailleText>
            </relatedElementInfo>
          </accessElement>
          <accessElement identifier="ae2">
            <contentLinkInfo itsLinkIdentifierRef="passage_3746_TAG_3_BEGIN" type="Text">
              <objectLink />
            </contentLinkInfo>
            <relatedElementInfo>
              <readAloud>
                <textToSpeechPronunciation>By</textToSpeechPronunciation>
                <textToSpeechPronunciationAlternate>by</textToSpeechPronunciationAlternate>
              </readAloud>
              <brailleText>
                <brailleTextString>by</brailleTextString>
              </brailleText>
            </relatedElementInfo>
          </accessElement>
          <accessElement identifier="ae3">
            <contentLinkInfo itsLinkIdentifierRef="passage_3746_TAG_2_BEGIN" type="Text">
              <objectLink />
            </contentLinkInfo>
            <relatedElementInfo>
              <readAloud>
                <textToSpeechPronunciation>Zullo.</textToSpeechPronunciation>
                <textToSpeechPronunciationAlternate>Zullo</textToSpeechPronunciationAlternate>
              </readAloud>
              <brailleText>
                <brailleTextString>Zullo</brailleTextString>
              </brailleText>
            </relatedElementInfo>
          </accessElement>
        </accessibilityInfo>
      </apipAccessibility>
    </content>
  </passage>
</itemrelease>